妈妈好啊  苏茜打招呼呢  是不是啊宝贝
Hello, Mum! Susie says hello, don't you, sweetheart?
多好啊  来挥挥手
That's it. Give a little wave.
我要说什么来着
Oh, what was I gonna say?
苏恩叔叔来电话了  向你问好
Uncle Soon called in, he says hello.
他总是说"你肯定很想她"
He keeps saying, "You must be missing her."
我说"她已经走了两年多了
I said, "She's been gone for over two years now,
我都习惯了"
I'm getting used to it!"
糟了信号要断了  肯定是太阳耀斑闹的
Oh, no, it's breaking up. It must be the solar flares.
说快点啊
Talk faster.
关于房贷的事
About the deposit on the house...
我和银行谈了
I've spoken to the bank...
红色星球
The Red Planet!
10分钟后日落  尤里  日光就快没了
Sun sets in ten minutes, Yuri. You're gonna lose the light.
好了
That's it.
在十号外部摄像头上看到你了
Got you on External Ten.
就快好了
Almost there.
径向夹具安装好了
That's the radial clamp down.
还有一件事
One more thing.
赶紧回到里面来  你的电力和氧气都不够了
Get back inside, you're using power and oxygen.
稍等
Oh, hold on.
把这个拍进去
Get this on camera.
-你觉得如何  -挺好的  不错啊尤里
- What do you think? - Hey, looks good! Nice one, Yuri.
你浪费了一整块太阳能板就为了做这个
You wasted an entire solar panel just to make that.
别这么严肃嘛  开个玩笑而已
Oh, lighten up. It's a joke.
我们走了这么远的路来到这个死寂的星球上
We come all this way, to an empty planet,
远离文明世界  然而我们做了什么呢
untouched by civilisation, and what do we do?
开这种无聊的玩笑
Put up cheap jokes.
这不好笑  这是污染
That's not funny, that's pollution.
-好玩吗  -我正说他呢
- Having fun? - I was just telling him.
这不像是你的水准  艾德
I expect better of you, Ed.
赶紧回去工作吧  所有人
Now get back to work, all of you.
真是漂亮
Ohh, beautiful.
转身
Rotate.
慢点
Slowly.
你被捕了
You are under arrest,
因为你擅自闯入  嘎吱嘎吱
for trespassing. Gadget-gadget.
表明你的姓名  军衔及来意
State your name, rank, and intention.
叫博士
The Doctor.
是博士
Doctor.
来玩的
Fun.
什么情况
What the hell?!
是个活人
It's a man!
火星上的人
A man on Mars!
-怎么会  -他穿着这件东西
- How? - He was wearing this thing.
我从没见过这种样式的防护服
I have never seen anything like it.
任务控制中心怎么说
What did Mission Control say?
太阳耀斑导致他们失联十个小时了
They're out of range for ten hours with the solar flares.
大家不要闲聊了
If we could cut the chat, everyone.
其实我觉得闲聊倒在其次
Actually, chat's second on my list,
首先是枪  指着我脑袋的这把
the first being gun, pointed at my head.
这样的话我的脑袋就排第二  闲聊排第三了
Which then puts my head second and chat third,
我想想  枪  脑袋和闲聊
I think. Gun, head, chat, yeah.
我讨厌列单子
I hate lists.
但那个东西会伤到人的  放下枪吧
But you could hurt someone with that, just... put it down.
那你就开心了
Oh, you'd like that.
不被枪指着  有谁会不开心吗
Can you find me someone who wouldn't?
我凭什么信任你
Why should I trust you?
因为我向你保证了
Because I give you my word.
而且离家6500万公里  你只能信我了
And, 40 million miles away from home, my word is all you've got.
让嘎吱看着他
Keep Gadget covering him.
嘎吱嘎吱
Gadget-gadget!
所以说控制那东西的是你
Oh, right, so you control that thing?
-自动响应手套  -没错
- Auto-glove response? - You got it.
右转
To the right...
-嘎吱嘎吱  -左转
- Gadget-gadget! - And to the left.
感觉有点颤颤巍巍的
It's a bit flimsy.
嘎吱嘎吱
Gadget-gadget!
-它必须得重复这句话吗  -我觉得好玩
- Does it have to keep saying that? - I think it's funny.
-我讨厌好玩的机器人  -抱歉  老大
- I hate funny robots. - Excuse me, boss.
电脑日志说咱们站里多了个人
Computer log says we've got an extra person on site.
这怎么可能
How's that possible?
让生态圆舱保持关闭
Keep the Bio-dome closed.
而且在公开通讯上  你要叫我船长
And when using open comms you call me Captain.
好  可是  他是谁啊
Yeah, but... who is it?
断了  她又挂我  你说说她怎么这样
Disconnected! She's cut me off. Can you believe her?
我们就好像园丁似的
It's like we're just... gardeners!
只要他们别来惹事  我就无所谓
As long as they leave us alone, that's fine with me.
瞧瞧这美人儿
Oh, you beauties!
你看看
Look at this!
最好多种一些
Better start planting some more,
又多了一张嘴要吃饭了
if there's an extra mouth to feed.
这可是地外第一片菜圃
The very first garden off Earth.
一切都是全新的
Everything brand-new.
伊甸园  我们该管这地方叫这个名字
Eden. That's what we should've called this place.
肯定是菲律宾  我敢打赌
It's the Philippines. I bet.
要是说火星上还有别的人  肯定是菲律宾人
If there's someone else on Mars, it's got to be the Philippines.
一直传说他们在造火箭
All those stories about them building a rocket.
阿德莱德肯定高兴坏了
Adelaide's gonna love that.
敢抢她的风头
Stealing her thunder.
真想看看她的表情
Mind you, worth it to see her face.
又或者是西班牙人
Or it could be the Spanish.
他们在搞一个秘密的太空链计划
They've kept that spacelink project under wraps.
你妹妹不是在他们那工作吗
Didn't your sister work for them?
你还好吗
Are you all right, mate?
拜托  别闹了
Come on, stop mucking about.
安迪
Andy?
你还好吗
Are you OK?
他肯定不是世界联邦的飞行员  我们会知道
He can't be a World State flight, we'd know about it.
因此他肯定是独立邦的人吧
Therefore, he's got to be one of the independents, yeah?
是布兰森遗产会的人吗
Was it the Branson inheritance lot?
他们筹划登陆火星好多年了
They've talked about a Mars shot for years.
好吧  没错  被你看穿了
Right, yes, OK, you got me.
-我是博士  你是  -得了吧
- So I'm the Doctor, and you are? - Oh, come on.
我们是史上第一批地外殖民者
We're the first off-world colonists in history.
地球上人人都知道我们的名字
Everyone on Planet Earth knows who we are.
你们是第一批
You're the first?
是火星上的第一批人类
The very first humans on Mars?
那  这就是
Then... this is...
猎刀一号基地
Bowie Base One.
第一号  2058年7月1日正式落成
Number one? Founded July 1st, 2058.
猎刀一号基地位于古谢夫环形山
Established Bowie Base One in the Gusev Crater...
-你们来了多久了  -17个月
- You've been here how long? - 17 months.
2059年
2059.
现在是2059年
It's 2059, right now.
我蠢透了  你就是阿德莱德·布洛克船长
My head is so stupid, you're Captain Adelaide Brooke!
还有艾德  你是副船长艾德华·高德
And Ed! You're Deputy Edward Gold.
塔拉克·伊塔  医疗官
Tarak Ital, MD.
尤里·克伦斯基护理师
Nurse Yuri Kerenski.
高级机师施特菲·埃利希
Senior Technician Steffi Ehrlich.
初级机师罗曼·格罗姆
Junior Technician Roman Groom.
地理学家米娅·班内特
Geologist Mia Bennett.
你才27岁啊
You're only 27 years old.
我说了  博士  人人都知道我们的名字
As I said, Doctor, everyone knows our names.
而他们也会永远记得
They'll never forget them.
今天是哪一天  告诉我具体的日期
What's the date, today? What is it? Tell me the exact date.
2059年11月21日
November 21st 2059.
好吧
Right.
-那好吧  -有什么问题吗
- OK. Fine. - Is there something wrong?
我的年龄怎么了
What's so important about my age?
我还是  走吧
I should... go.
我真的该走了
I... really should go.
我很抱歉  我真的由衷地抱歉
I'm sorry. I'm sorry with all of my hearts.
但眼下就是那种极少的我别无选择的时候
But it's one of those very rare times when I've got no choice.
我实在是太荣幸了
It's been an honour.
真的  能见到各位  我太荣幸了
Seriously, a... very great honour to meet you all.
火星先驱
The Martian pioneers.
感谢你们
Oh, thank you.
嘎吱嘎吱
Gadget-gadget.
谢谢
Thank you.
不是还有两个吗  等下
There's the other two. Hold on...
玛格丽特·凯恩和安德鲁·斯通
Margaret Cain and Andrew Stone.
玛吉  如果你想见一下接下来的五年里
Maggie... if you want to meet the only new human being
你能看见的唯一的新面孔
that you're gonna see in the next five years,
你最好来看看
better come take a look.
那是什么
What was that?
我真的该走了
Ohh, I really should go.
这里是控制中心  生态圆舱请立即回报
This is Central. Bio-dome report immediately.
让我看圆舱的监控
Show me the Bio-dome.
-内部摄像头坏了  -让我看外部的
- Internal cameras are down. - Show me the exterior.
我去看看
I'm going over.
-博士  跟我来  -这个  抱歉
- Doctor, with me. - Yeah... I'm sorry, erm...
我很想帮你们  但我真的必须得走了
I'd love to help, but I'm leaving, right now.
拿走他的太空服  锁起来
Take his spacesuit, lock it up.
你一来就出了这种事  你哪都别想去
This started as soon as you arrived, so you're not going anywhere.
除非跟着我
Except with me.
嘎吱嘎吱
Gadget-gadget.
米娅的年龄为什么这么重要
What's so important about Mia's age?
你说她才27岁
You said she's only 27,
为什么要强调这个  什么意思
why does it matter, what did you mean?
我只是  一张嘴就情不自禁地说各种话
Oh, I just... open my mouth and words come out.
都是随便说说而已
They don't make much sense.
-可不是吗  -多谢了  医生
- Telling me. - Thank you, Doctor.
-不客气  博士  -嘎吱嘎吱
- Any time, Doctor. - Gadget-gadget!
我说没说过我不喜欢机器人
I hate robots. Did I say?
它也不喜欢你呢
Yeah, and he's not too fond of you.
-机器人怎么了  -不是机器人  而是人
- What's wrong with robots? - It's not the robots, it's the people.
把它们打扮起来  还让它们出声
Dressing them up and giving them silly voices.
太贬低它们了
You're reducing them.
是吗  我一朋友
Yeah. Friend of mine,
她把自己的家务机器人打扮得跟狗似的
she made her domestic robot look like a dog.
狗嘛  就不一样了
Ah, well, dogs. That's different.
但嘎吱我是用施工机器人改造成的
But I adapted Gadget out of the worker drones.
那些东西可大了
Those things are huge!
防护罩从轨道降下时就是它们建造了这个站
They built this place when the shell was lowered down from orbit.
它们的强度可以达到15吨...
They've got a strength capacity of 15 tons per...
本通讯频道仅用于关键通讯
The channel is open for essential communications only.
抱歉
Sorry.
喜欢那些机器人
Love those drones.
我读过好多你的报道  阿德莱德船长
I've read all that stuff about you, Captain Adelaide.
但有件事他们都没说  这个任务值得吗
But one thing they never said, was it worth it? The mission?
我们的土壤分析得出了非常好的结果
We've got excellent results from the soil analysis.
不是  我是指整个这一切
No, but all of it.
因为他们说你牺牲了一切
Cos they say you sacrificed everything.
将毕生精力投入到登陆火星上
Devoted your whole life to get here.
地球上已经乱作一团了
It's been chaos back home.
漫长的40年
40 long years.
气候变化  臭氧空洞  还有原油枯竭
The climate, the ozone, the oil apocalypse.
我们差点就灭亡了
We almost reached extinction.
而飞离那一切
Then to fly above that...
来到一个没有烟雾污染的地方
to stand on a world with no smoke,
这里唯一的光源就是太阳
where the only straight line is the sunlight...
当然是值得的
Yes. It's worth it.
所以我才想一睹阿德莱德·布洛克的风采
That's the Adelaide Brooke I always wanted to meet.
灵魂中满是星光的女人
The woman with starlight in her soul.
那是什么
What's that?
-是玛吉  -别碰她
- It's Maggie. - Don't touch her!
我知道程序  玛吉  听得见我吗
I know the procedure. Maggie, can you hear me?
我是塔拉克  玛吉
It's Tarak. Maggie?
她没事  她还有呼吸  还活着
It's OK. She's still breathing. She's alive.
尤里  已找到玛格丽特·凯恩
Yuri, I've got Margaret Cain,
头部受伤  需要医疗包
head trauma. I need a full medpack.
拿到了  医疗包马上就到
I've got it. Medpack on its way.
-我去帮忙  -船长因故不在时
- I'm going to help! - In the absence of the Captain,
指挥官就是你  你必须得待在指挥中心
you're in charge, sir! You've got to stay in the Dome!
别碰她  用手套
Don't touch her, use the gloves.
听他的  送她去医疗舱
Do what he says. Get her to sickbay.
把她隔离起来
Put her in isolation.
我们继续朝生态圆舱进发
We're going to the Bio-dome.
塔拉克跟我来  尤里来照顾她
Tarak, with me, Yuri can take care of her.
艾德  你回去
Ed, go back.
嘎吱  保持警戒  盯紧这片区域
Gadget, stand guard, keep an eye on this area.
-嘎吱嘎吱  -船长你会需要我的
- Gadget-gadget! - Captain, you're gonna need me.
失踪的船员只有安迪了
Andy's the only other crew member out here,
而如果这不是意外的话
and if that wasn't an accident...
那他就失控了
then he's gone wild.
你这是擅离职守  这是给你的正式警告
You've deserted your post. Consider that an official warning.
赶紧回到岗位去  博士
Now, get back to work. Doctor?
船长  我们听见的从生态圆舱传来的声音
Captain. That sound we heard from the Bio-dome,
我分析了一下
I've run it through diagnostics.
根据电脑分析  那是安迪的声音
According to the computer, it's... it's Andy.
其声音特征登记为安迪·斯通
It registers as the voice-print of Andy Stone.
明白
Understood.
-请复查  谢谢  -气压稳定
- Double-check, thanks. - Air pressure stabilised.
安德鲁
Andrew?
安德鲁·斯通  我是布洛克船长
Andrew Stone? It's Captain Brooke.
安迪快汇报  我要看见你  你在哪
Andy, report. I need to see you. Where are you?
好了
There you go.
-那是什么仪器  -起子
- What's that device? - Screwdriver.
你到底是博士还是维修工
Are you the Doctor or the Janitor?
我也不知道  都挺适合我的
I don't know, sounds like me.
宇宙维修工
The maintenance man of the universe.
你就待在我身边  不要走远
You, stay with me, don't step out of my sight.
塔拉克  去南侧外部门  确保其紧闭密封
Tarak, go to External Door South, make sure it's intact.
-是  长官  -成就不小啊
- Yes, ma'am. - Quite an achievement.
一万年来火星第一朵花
First flower on Mars in 10,000 years.
而且你们还在种菜
And you're growing veg!
是那帮人  他们计划要做一顿圣诞大餐
It's that lot, they're already planning Christmas dinner.
去年吃的是脱水蛋白质
Last year it was dehydrated protein,
今年他们想吃点真正的菜
this year they want the real thing.
完全合理嘛  毕竟是圣诞节
Still, fair enough. Christmas.
如果必须过的话
If we must.
-连鸟都有  -这是项目的一部分
- You've got birds! - It's part of the project,
控制虫群的规模
to keep the insect population down.
好兆头
Good sign.
-怎么说  -它们还活着
- In what way? - Well, they're still alive.
船长  好消息
Captain? Good news.
是玛吉  她醒了  恢复意识了
It's Maggie. She's awake, she's back with us.
你还好吗  大兵
Hey. How are you, Soldier?
你慢慢来
Just take it easy.
你还记得是怎么回事吗
Can you remember what happened?
我只是在
I was just...
工作
working.
然后就  在这里醒过来了
Then I woke... woke up here.
安迪呢  我们找不到他  他没事吧
What about Andy? We can't find him. Was he all right?
我不知道  我只是
I don't know, I just...
如果你想起来什么  立即向我汇报
If you remember anything, let me know straightaway.
尤里  她知道她是怎么到通道里的吗
Yuri, does she know how she ended up in the tunnel?
不要干扰通讯
And keep the comms clear.
任何事都要通过我  明白了吗
Everything goes through me, got that?
让我出去吧  我没事  就是有点晕
Come on. Just let me out of here. I'm fine. Just groggy.
你知道规定的
You know the rules.
隔离24小时
24 hours.
安迪
Andy?
Andy!
安迪
你在这呢
There you are.
你还好吗
Are you all right?
安迪
Andy...
安德鲁
Andrew.
看着我
Look at me.
可是大笔的银子早就花出去了【】
A tam uzhe sploshniye zatradi poshli.
【】
No ya yemu I govoryu. Ty shto opyat...
那是你兄弟吗
Is that your brother?
录像回放而已  太阳耀斑还没结束呢
It's only a repeat. The solar flares are still up.
你还好吧
Are you OK?
挺好  就是  你懂的
Yeah, just... y'know...
说了多少次了  根本不听...【】
Govoril yemu skolko raz uzhe. Nichego ne pomogaet...
他总是能把我逗乐
He makes me laugh, though.
是他丈夫  花起钱来都不过脑子的
It's his husband, he spends money like... an idiot!
去年为了给米哈伊尔过生日
Last year, for Mikhail's birthday,
他说  "不用给我买礼物"
he said, "Don't buy me anything."
"咱们省点钱"
"Let's save money."
乔治说  "行  那好"
Georg says, "Fine, OK."
然后等他生日到了
His birthday comes around,
结果乔治给他买了辆车
turns out Georg has bought him a car!
还是顶配
Top of the range.
而关键是  他用的是米哈伊尔的信用章
And the thing is, he's used Mikhail's credit stamp!
米哈就说了  我这是自己掏钱给自己买的啊
So Mik's saying, that means I bought it myself!
乔治说  "情意无价"
Georg says, "It's the thought that counts."
他住哪
Where does he live?
就在达吉斯坦
Oh, just outside Dagestan.
-那是哪  -就在里海边上  你看
- Where's that? - On the Caspian Sea. Here you go...
-在海边  -严格来讲那是个大湖
- By the sea. - Well, technically it's more of a lake.
地球有好多水
Earth is so much water.
是啊
Yeah...
瞧瞧她  6500万公里开外
Just look at her. 40 million miles away.
真是太美了
It has so much beauty.
我们会喜欢那个世界的
We should like that world.
这里是医疗舱  出事了  玛吉她...
This is sickbay, we have a situation. Maggie's condition has...
我不知道  我也不知道是怎么回事
I don't know, I don't know what it is.
有水  涌出来了
It's water, just... pouring out.
尤里  冷静点
Yuri, calm down.
告诉我她到底怎么了
Just tell me what's happened to her.
她嘴边的皮肤  开裂了
The skin is... sort of broken around the mouth.
而她在向外流水  就好像她溺水了
And she's exuding water. Like she's drowning.
塔拉克  这个区域不安全  我们撤退
Tarak, this area's unsafe, we're going back.
塔拉克
Tarak?
-塔拉克  -他刚才在哪
- Tarak! - Where was he?
尤里  继续关着她
Yuri, keep her contained.
最大强度封锁舱门  我这就过去
Seal the door at maximum. I'm on my way!
安迪  快放了他
Andy... just leave him alone.
-离他远点  -我来帮你  我保证
- Step away from him. - I can help, I promise.
我能帮你  你放开他
I can help, just leave that man alone!
安迪求你了  把你的手放开他  听我说
Andy, I'm asking you, please, take your hand away from him and listen to me.
好了
There now...
这样好多了  是不是
that's better. Hmm?
那么  你就是安迪了
So... you must be Andy.
你好
Hello.
我们得走了
We've got to go.
把门锁设定为最大强度
Set the seals at maximum!
什么鬼
What the hell?
那不是玛吉了  她到底怎么了
That's not Maggie. What's happened to her?
尤里  她到底是什么
Yuri. What IS she?
船长  我们需要你立即赶回来
Captain, we need you back here.
告诉我玛吉已被控制住  能确认吗  艾德
Just tell me that Maggie is contained. Can you confirm, Ed?
确认
Confirmed.
她被锁住了
She's locked in.
在我回来之前继续监视
Keep surveillance till I get back.
切断一切水源供应
And close down all water supplies.
全部管道和出水口  一点都不要喝
All pipes and outlets, don't consume anything.
大家都听到了吗
Have you got that, everyone?
这是命令  不准喝水
That's an order. Don't drink the water.
碰都不能碰  一滴都不行
Don't even touch it. Not one drop.
你能说话吗
Can you talk?
人体60%都是水  所以就成了完美宿主
Human beings are 60% water, which makes them the perfect host.
有什么目的
What for?
我不知道  也不会知道了
I don't know. I never will...
因为我得走了
Because I've got to go.
不管发生了什么  我都不能查到底了
Whatever's started here, I can't see it to the end.
我不能
I can't.
-这是气密门吧  -所以也能隔水
- This thing's airtight, yeah? - And therefore watertight.
这得看水有多聪明了
Depends how clever the water is.
他们在短路系统
They're fusing the system.
弃船
Abandon ship!
博士  我们没时间了
Doctor, we haven't got time!
他们比我们跑得快  我们需要代步工具
They can run faster than us, we need a lift!
嘎吱嘎吱
Hey! Gadget-gadget.
-站到我身后  -这东西时速只有3公里
- Get on behind me! - That thing goes at two miles an hour!
现在不是了
Not any more!
相信我
Trust me.
-嘎吱嘎吱  -继续嘎吱吧
- Gadget-gadget! - Keep gadget!
中央圆舱的气闸安装有哈丁格锁
The Central Dome airlocks have got Hardinger seals.
他们绝对不可能进来
There's no way they can get in.
-快点  快点  -嘎吱嘎吱
- Come on, come on! - Gadget-gadget.
你不是讨厌机器人吗
I thought you hated robots!
没错
I do!
安全了  这里完全密封  他们进不来
We're safe. It's hermetically sealed. They can't get in.
水有的是耐心  阿德莱德
Water is patient, Adelaide.
水会静静等待
Water just waits.
水能磨平悬崖
It wears down the clifftops,
夷平山峦  甚至整个世界
the mountains, the whole of the world.
水总是会赢  快来
Water always wins. Come on!
生态圆舱通道已失去联系
Bio-dome Tunnel is out of bounds.
安迪和塔拉克被感染  重复  被感染
Andy and Tarak are infected, repeat, infected.
不得进行任何接触
Make no contact.
他们只要动一动就告诉我  我这就去医疗舱
And if they make a slightest move, tell me. I'm going to the Medical Dome.
我的天  这么远  都可以骑自行车了
Blimey, it's a distance. You could do with bikes in this place.
一磅载重就要消耗三吨燃油
Every pound in weight equals three tons of fuel.
我知道
Yeah, I know.
可是  自行车啊
But... bikes!
这扇门有哈丁格锁吗
Has that door got a Hardinger seal?
没有  就是普通锁
No, just basic.
那她一扑到门上我们就撤  明白了吗
Then the moment she heads for the door, we evacuate. Got that?
脉搏很低
Pulse is low.
大脑电活动看起来一团乱
Electrical activity in the brain seems to be going haywire.
-她能说话吗  -不知道
- Can she talk? - Don't know.
在发现病变之前她还在说话  不过
She was talking before we noticed the change, but...
玛吉  听得见我吗  知道我是谁吗
Maggie? Can you hear me? Do you know who I am?
我是你的指挥官  阿德莱德·布洛克船长
Your commanding officer, Captain Adelaide Brooke.
你能告诉我是怎么回事吗
Can you tell me what happened?
-那是什么语  -上古北火星语
- What language is that? - Ancient North Martian.
别胡闹了
Don't be ridiculous.
-但她似乎听懂了  -而且她的眼睛变了
- It's like she recognised it. - And her eyes are different.
都变清澈了
They're clear,
就好像她更像人类
like she's closer to human.
我看离人类还差得远
Not close enough for me.
-你们的水是从哪里采的  -冰原
- Where do you get your water from? - The ice field.
所以我们才选择了这个环形山
That's why we chose the crater,
就在一片地下冰原上方
we're on top of an underground glacier.
丰富的水  真好
Tons of water. Marvellous.
但每一滴水都是过滤了的
But every single drop is filtered.
-经过滤筛  是安全的  -看来是挺安全
- It's screened, it's safe. - Looks like it, yeah.
如果冰层下冻着什么  某种病毒生命体
If something was frozen down there... A viral life form,
在冰块里被保存了这么久
held in the ice for all those years...
你看她的嘴  都黢黑开裂了
Look at her mouth. All blackened,
就好像是某种裂变
like there's some sort of fission.
这东西  不管是什么
This thing, whatever it is,
不止是藏在水里  还能产生水
doesn't just hide in water, it CREATES water.
告诉我你想要什么
Tell me what you want.
她之前看着屏幕
She was looking at the screen.
看着地球  她想要地球
At Earth. She wanted Earth.
一个充满水的世界
A world full of water.
船长  来一下
Captain. With me.
我很抱歉  但这是一种未知感染源
I'm sorry, but it's an unknown infection
而且还在扩散  这就需要启动一号程序
and it's spreading. That demands Action Procedure One.
-你以为我不知道吗  -我觉得你需要提醒
- D'you think I don't know that? - I think you need reminding.
也对
Yeah.
-至少我还是有点长处的  -偶尔吧
- Well, at least I'm good for something. - Now and again.
你这简直就是在夸我
That's almost a compliment.
看来事情真的很严重了
Things must be serious.
抱歉  一号程序是疏散的意思吧
Sorry, sorry, but... Action One, that means evacuation, yeah?
我们要回家了  我是布洛克船长
We're going home. This is Captain Brooke.
我宣布执行一号程序  重复  全体船员
I'm declaring Action One, repeat to all crewmembers,
执行一号程序  立即生效  疏散整个基地
this is Action One, with immediate effect. Evacuate the base.
我来储存中央电脑  米娅
I'll store the Central Computer, Mia,
将关键物资之外的载重卸掉  罗曼动起来
strip the cargo down to essentials. Roman, on your feet!
-但我们走了这么远  -嘎吱嘎吱
- But we came all this way. - Gadget-gadget!
那你跟你的小机器人吻别吧
And you can kiss that robot goodbye,
太沉了  赶紧把它收拾进仓库  快点
it's too heavy. Now shove it in storage and hurry up!
施特菲  你估计飞船需要多久才能发射
Steffi, what's your estimate on shuttle viability?
需要飞行九个月
It's a nine-month flight,
至少需要三个小时才能装载完所需物资
it'll take three hours to load what we need.
给你20分钟  汇报下安迪和塔拉克的情况
You've got 20 minutes. And give me a report on Andy and Tarak.
他们还在生态圆舱的通道里
Still in the Bio-dome Tunnel.
就这么站着  好像在等什么
They're just standing there. Like they're waiting.
盯紧了他们  给你的时间减到15分钟
Keep an eye on them. And make that 20 minutes 15!
艾德  准备好飞船  直接进入发射状态
Ed, line up the shuttle, go straight to ignition status.
马上去
Doing it now.
-那玛吉呢  -她留下
- But what about Maggie? - She stays behind,
船上没地方关着她
we've got no way to contain her on board.
封闭这个区域  把电力直接转到飞船
Close this place down. I want the power directed to the shuttle.
-唯一的问题就是  -多谢你  博士
- Of course, the only problem is... - Thank you, Doctor,
我们会归还你的太空服  祝你好运
your spacesuit will be returned. And good luck.
问题在于  这东西很聪明
The problem is, this thing is clever.
它不感染生态圆舱里的鸟类和昆虫
It didn't infect the birds or the insects in Bio-dome,
而是选择了人类  你们被盯上了
it chose the humans. You were chosen.
而我告诉你  阿德莱德  水等得起
And I told you, Adelaide, water can wait.
塔拉克立即就发作了
Tarak changed straight away,
但玛吉被感染后  它却隐藏在她体内
but when Maggie was infected it stayed hidden inside her.
毫无疑问是为了渗透中央圆舱  也就是说
No doubt, so it could infiltrate the Central Dome. Which means...
我们中间任何人都有可能被感染
Any one of us could already be infected.
我们都喝了同样的水
We've all been drinking the same water.
而如果你把这东西带回地球
And if you take that back to Earth...
-一滴  哪怕就一滴  -可是
- One drop. Just one drop. - But...
我们只是推测是感染
we're only presuming infection.
但如果我们能查明这东西是怎么进来的
If we can find out how this thing got through,
什么时候进来的
when it got through...
尤里  继续执行一号程序
Yuri, continue with Action One.
我要去检查冰原
I'm going to inspect the ice-field.
好吧  我该走了
Right. I should leave.
我终于该走了
Finally, I should leave.
尤里好哥们  我完全没必要去看冰原的吧
Yuri, me old mate, no point in me seeing the ice-field.
完全没必要
No point at all.
没有
Nope.
阿德莱德
Adelaide!
我就说么  有自行车多好
All I'm saying is, bikes.
那种折叠的小自行车  不沉的
Little foldaway bikes, don't weigh a thing.
抱歉了
I'm sorry.
就算她穿过了医疗圆舱
Even if she gets past the Medical Dome,
她也绝对过不了这边的哈丁格锁  对吧
she'll never get past the Hardinger seal at this end, right?
只是我们说而已
So we keep saying.
摄像头坏了
Camera's down.
看不到她了
We've lost her.
人们很久以前就流传着火星的传说
They tell legends of Mars, from long ago.
说有一个发达高贵的种族在雪原中建起了帝国
Of a fine and noble race who built an empire out of snow.
-寒冰勇士  -我没时间听故事了
- The Ice Warriors. - I haven't got time for stories.
或许他们在下面发现了什么
Perhaps they found something down there.
用他们的神通和智慧将其冻在了下面
Used their might and their wisdom to freeze it.
博士  我们得发现水处理程序中的任何异常
Doctor! We need to find any sort of change in the water process.
我们需要确定感染的发生时间
We've got to date the infection.
拒绝访问
Access denied.
你看起来不像是个胆小鬼
You don't look like a coward.
但你一直都想走
But all you've wanted to do is leave.
你对我们了解这么多
You know so much about us.
-你们出名嘛  -但你似乎知道更多
- Well, you're famous. - But it's like you know more.
这一刻  时间中的这一刻  就像
This moment, this precise moment in time, it's like...
当然只是推论而已  我也不确定  但是
I mean, it's only a theory, what do I know? But...
我认为  时间中的某些时刻是固定的
I think... certain moments in time are fixed.
微小的  珍贵的时刻
Tiny, precious moments.
其他一切都在变动  一切皆有可能
Everything else is in flux, anything can happen,
但这些特定的时刻  一定是不变的
but those certain moments, they have to stand.
这个火星基地
This base, on Mars,
还有你  阿德莱德·布洛克
with you, Adelaide Brooke,
就是一个关键时刻
this is one vital moment.
此刻发生的事一定会发生
What happens here must always happen.
是什么事
Which is what?
我不知道
I don't know.
我想应该是一些美妙的事
I think something wonderful happens.
从50年前就开始了  对不对
Something that started 50 years ago, isn't that right?
我从没跟任何人提起过
I've never told anyone that.
你告诉了你女儿
You told your daughter.
而也许有一天  她会把这个故事告诉她女儿
And maybe, one day, she tells the story to her daughter.
地球被盗  被搬运到宇宙另一边的故事
The day the Earth was stolen and moved across the universe.
而你
And you...
我看见了戴立克
I saw the Daleks.
我们向天上望去
We looked up,
天空发生了变化
the sky had changed.
人人都惊慌失措了
Everyone was running and screaming.
而我父亲紧紧抱着我
And my father took hold of me...
待在这
Stay here!
不要乱跑
Don't move.
我得出去
I've got to go out.
去找你妈妈  但我一定会回来  我保证
I'm gonna find your mother, but I'm coming back, I promise you.
我会回来的
I'm coming back.
我再也没见到他
I never saw him again.
还有我的母亲
Nor my mother.
谁都没能找到他们
They were never found.
但是在街上
But out on the streets,
到处都是慌乱
there was panic
和烈焰
and burning.
我走到窗户旁
I went to the window.
然后  在空中
And there in the sky...
我看到了  博士
I saw it, Doctor.
它也看到了我
And it saw me.
它盯着我看
It stared at me.
直直看到了我的心里
It looked right into me.
然后
And then...
它就这么飞走了
It simply went away.
就在那晚  我知道了
I knew, that night,
我知道我会跟着它
I knew I would follow it.
但不是为了复仇
But not for revenge.
那有什么意义呢
What would be the point of that?
所以你才这么了不起
That's what makes you remarkable.
所以你才能创造历史
And that's how you create history.
什么意思
What do you mean?
想象一下吧  阿德莱德
Imagine it, Adelaide.
你的旅程
If you began a journey
拉开了人类挺进群星的大幕
that takes the human race all the way out to the stars.
起点就是你
It begins with you.
而你的外孙女  是你启发了她
And then your granddaughter, you inspire her.
所以30年后  苏茜·方塔纳·布洛克
So that in 30 years Susie Fontana Brooke
才会成为驾驶第一艘光速飞船抵达比邻星的人
is the pilot of the first lightspeed ship to Proxima Centauri.
然后你们无往不至
And then everywhere.
她的孩子  还有她孩子的孩子继续探索着
With her children, and her children's children forging the way,
远达龙星和冬女王星系的天廓
to the Dragon Star, the Celestial Belt of the Winter Queen,
还有水蛇虫洞的地图
the Map of the Water Snake Wormholes...
还有一天
One day,
布洛克家的后代甚至会爱上坦多尼亚王子
a Brooke will fall in love with a Tandonian prince,
而他们开启了一个全新的种族
that's the start of a whole new species.
但一切都源起于你  阿德莱德
But everything starts with you, Adelaide.
从50年前  到今天  到这里
From 50 years ago, to right here, today.
想象一下吧
Imagine.
你是谁
Who are you?
为什么要告诉我这些
Why are you telling me this?
博士
Doctor?
为什么告诉我
Why tell me?
为了安慰你
As consolation.
安迪·斯通
Andy Stone.
他昨天登录了
He logged on yesterday.
维护日志21.20  2059年11月
Maintenance log, 21.20, November 2059.
三号水过滤器炸锅了
Number three water filter's bust.
你猜怎么着  他们送来的替换件不兼容
Guess what, the spares they sent don't fit.
多意外啊
What a surprise.
记录完毕
Over and out.
过滤器
A filter.
一台小过滤器坏掉  "洪魔"就涌进来了
One tiny little filter and then the Flood.
但那就意味着感染是今天才渗透进来的
But that means the infection arrived today!
而生态圆舱的水要一周才能循环出去
And the water's only cycled out of the biodome after a week.
我们其余的人不可能被感染  我们可以走
The rest of us can't be infected. We can leave!
艾德  我们是安全的
Ed, we're clean!
进行的怎么样了
How are we doing?
飞船已启动  第一阶段
Shuttle's active, stage one!
我没时间装载蛋白质包了
I haven't got time to convey the protein packs.
如果你们想要食物
If you want food you're
就只能用手拿着了  开始装吧
gonna have to carry it by hand. Start loading!
马上
Right now!
-你说得对  博士  -什么
- You were right, Doctor. - What about?
自行车
Bikes!
回你的飞船吧  我救我的人  你救你自己
Now get to your ship. I'm saving my people, you save yourself.
我知道这是什么时候
I know what this moment is.
是我们逃走的时候  快走吧你
It's the moment we escape, now get out.
所有人  快一点
Everyone, stay...
我来替换它们  罗曼  你呢
I'll swap them round. Roman, what about you?
蛋白质包30-36号
Protein-packs 30 to 36.
施特菲把中央保存箱扔了  我们用不着
Steffi, ditch the central containers. We don't need them.
-41  42和43号  -41号在这
- Units 41, 42 and 43. - Unit 41 is here.
罗曼去调高氧气膜的密度
Roman try to condense the oxygen membranes,
可以减少10磅体重  快点  快去
we can lose ten pounds. Faster, come on!!
艾德  燃料喷射器怎样了
Ed, how's the fuel jets?
30秒后冷却
Cooling down in about 30 seconds.
那是什么动静
What the hell's that noise?
米娅  你们都闭嘴
Mia, you lot, shut up.
是模块探测器
It's the module sensors.
外部12号  摄像头失效
Exterior 12. The cameras are down,
但模块上方检测到压力
but there's pressure on top of the module.
有两个信号在我们上方
Two signals right above us.
这就意味着
That means...
他们在屋顶上
They're on the roof?!
他们是怎么进入圆舱的
How did they get inside the Dome?
他们利用维修竖井
They used the maintenance shafts.
维修井是开放的  他们没穿太空服
The shaft's open, they haven't got spacesuits.
他们靠水呼吸
They breathe water.
-但它们会冻住的  -它们有内部裂变系统
- But they'd freeze. - They've got that internal fission.
但我们是安全的  他们进不来  对吧
But we're safe, they can't get through, can they?
对不对
Can they?
这是个气密舱室
This place is airtight!
它们能穿过来吗
Can it get through?
-艾德  能穿过来吗  -我不知道
- Ed? Can it get through? - I don't know!
水自身不会动  但却有一定的持久性
Water itself isn't motile, but it has some sort of persistence.
大家都听好
Everyone, listen to me!
上面是3米厚的复合钢板
That's ten feet of steel-combination up there.
我们需要全部蛋白质包  不然就会饿死
We need all the protein-packs or we're gonna starve,
所以快点干活
now keep working!
罗曼  看着点天花板
Roman! Watch the ceiling!
艾德  去飞船  点火吧
Ed, get to the shuttle, fire it up.
我能比他们搬得更多  船长
I can carry more than this lot, Captain.
-这是命令  -是  船长
- That's an order! - Captain.
拒绝访问
Access denied.
告诉我发生什么了
Tell me what happens.
我也不知道
I don't know.
你当然知道
Yes, you do.
告诉我
Now tell me.
-你应该去帮其他人  -告诉我
- You should be with the others. - Tell me!
我可以增加那个气闸里的气压  把你压死
I could ramp up the pressure in that airlock and crush you.
但你不会
Except you won't.
你本可以朝安迪·斯通开枪  但你没有
You could have shot Andy Stone, but you didn't.
我喜欢你这一点
I loved you for that.
想象一下
Imagine...
想象你知道些什么
Imagine you knew something...
想象你在某个地方  比如说庞贝
Imagine you found yourself somewhere, I don't know, Pompeii.
想象你身处庞贝
Imagine you were in Pompeii.
那跟眼下的事情有什么关系
What the hell's that got to do with it?
你想救他们
You tried to save them.
但你的干预反而推动了事情的发生
But in doing so you make it happen.
不管我做什么
Anything I do...
也只会让事情发生
... just makes it happen.
船长  这边需要你
Captain, we need you right now!
我还在
I'm still here.
你要执行一号程序
You're taking Action One.
还有另外四个标准行动程序
There are four more standard action procedures.
而五号程序是
And Action Five is...?
引爆
Detonation.
最后选项
The final option.
核装置就安装在中央圆舱的核心
The nuclear device at the heart of the Central Dome.
今天  2059年11月21日
Today, on the 21st November 2059,
布洛克船长引爆了核装置
Captain Brooke activates that device,
将基地和包括她在内的所有船员全部摧毁
taking the base and all her crew members with her.
没人知道原因
No-one ever knows why.
但你们拯救了地球
But you were saving Earth.
所以你的外孙女才会备受鼓舞
That's what inspires your granddaughter.
她带领着你们人类深入银河系
She takes your people out into the galaxy,
就因为你
because you die,
死在了火星
on Mars.
今天  你会死
You die, today.
而她飞进深空
She flies out there...
就好像她想要去找你
Like she's trying to meet you.
我不会死
I won't die.
绝对不会
I will not.
但你的死  开创了未来
But your death creates the future.
帮帮我
Help me.
你为什么不肯帮我  博士
Why won't you help, Doctor?
既然你知道这一切  为什么不出手改变呢
If you know all of this, why can't you change it?
-我不能  -你就不能想想办法吗
- I can't. - Why can't you find a way?
-你可以告诉我  -我很抱歉  但是不行
- You could tell me, I don't know... - I'm sorry, but I can't.
有时我可以  我也会做
Sometimes I can, sometimes I do,
大多数时候我都可以救一些人
most times I can save someone,
或某一个人
or anyone.
但你不行
But not you.
你这一生都在想
You wondered all your life
为什么那个戴立克饶了你  我认为它知道
why that Dalek spared you. I think it knew.
你的死  是时间里永恒的定点
Your death is fixed, in time, for ever.
必须这样
And that's right.
你也会死在这里
You'll die here too.
不会
No.
谁会救你
What's gonna save you?
阿德莱德·布洛克船长
Captain Adelaide Brooke.
你该死
Damn you.
水  进水了
Water! We've got water!
船长  快退后
Captain! Get back!
退后  船长
Get back! Captain!
别碰  罗曼  快退后
Don't touch it, Roman. Get back!
全体放弃这个区域  快上飞船
Everyone, we're abandoning this section, get to the shuttle!
尤里带路  B区走廊  快去
Yuri, lead the way, Section B Corridor, now.
拿上那个  还有那个
Get that! And that!
快关上
Close it!
-尤里你被水碰到了吗  -我安全
- Yuri, did that water touch you? - I'm safe...
它碰到你了吗
Did it touch you?
-尤里你碰到水了吗  -我安全  没沾水
- Yuri, did that water touch you? - I'm clean... I'm dry.
大家  B区无法通过  听我说
Everyone, Section B is out. Listen to me!!
能带多少包就带多少  我们绕路
Take every pack that you can, we'll go round,
我们从F区过去
we'll make our way out through Section F.
授权向F区转移  米娅你拿上紧急储存
Transferring authorization, Section F. Mia you take the redline stock!
大家赶快
And hurry up!
施特菲  退后
Steffi, get back!
施特菲  往后退
Steffi, keep back.
-退后  -施特菲  快退后
- Get back!! - Steffi!! Get back, Steffi!!
-屏蔽门  -退到门里  关上门
- Screen! - Get back to the door! Close the door!
施特菲我们会来救你的  一定会救你的
Steffi, we'll come get you, OK? We'll come get you!
-施特菲  -船长
- Steffi! - Captain!
我们把检修口给你打开  让你从后面出来
We'll open the access panel, we'll get you out through the back.
快点出去  快走
Get out of here, move it!
船长  水进来了
Captain, it's inside!
-施特菲  -施特菲  退后
- Steffi! - Steffi, get back!
我们就来  施特菲  坚持住
We're coming! Steffi, hold on!
检修口被焊死了  船长
The access panel's fused, Captain.
我们打不开
We can't open it.
我们过不去
We can't get through!
我们无能为力了
There's nothing we can do.
我动不了了
I can't move!
你好啊妈妈  你好火星
Hallo, Mutti. Hallo, Mars!
来打招呼啊
Sag hallo.
施特菲  能听见我吗
Steffi! Can you hear me?
我的天啊
Oh, my God.
出去  快出去
Out! Get out!
艾德  我们要绕远了  你那边怎样
Ed, we're going round the long way, how are we doing?
所有系统上线100%  一点问题都没有
All systems online, 100%. Not a single delay!
别担心  船长  我们就要飞走了
Don't you worry, Captain, we are gonna fly!
我需要空气  立即往F区注入空气
I need air in Section F right now.
所有人
All of you...
三号舱锁定  四号舱锁定
Locking chamber three, locking chamber four...
继续找
Keep looking!
五号门开了
Gate five is open!
六号门开了
Gate six is open!
快点  快去
Quickly, come on!
罗曼  快点  跟我来
Roman, come on, with me!
你们最好先走
You'd better go.
别在那干站着了  快走
Don't just stand there, move!
你们最好不要管我了
You'd really better go without me.
我很抱歉  船长
I'm sorry, Captain.
就一滴
One drop.
罗曼
Roman!
别管他了  来吧
Leave him, come on.
-不能丢下他不管啊  -来吧
- We can't just leave him! - Come on.
放开我  罗曼
Let me go! Roman!
-船长  飞船不行了  -你什么意思
- Captain. The shuttle is down. - What the hell d'you mean?
被破坏了
Compromised.
-是玛吉  -快出来
- It was Maggie. - Get out of there!
太晚了
Too late.
他们想用这艘船入侵地球
They want this ship to get to Earth.
我没得选择
Got no choice.
我真不喜欢  阿德莱德
Hated it, Adelaide.
这个该死的工作
This bloody job.
你一直没有给我机会
You never gave me a chance.
你一直不肯原谅我
You never could forgive me.
再见了
See you later.
我们失去氧气了
We're losing oxygen!
舱壁破了
The hull is broken!!
我不只是个普通的时间领主
I'm not just a Time Lord,
我是最后的时间领主
I'm the Last of the Time Lords.
他们再也回不来了  永远不会
They'll never come back, not now.
我还有塔迪斯  老样子  最后的时间领主
I've got a TARDIS. Same old life, last of the Time Lords.
他们死了  一切也随他们而去
And they died, took it all with them.
世界之墙关闭了  每个世界都独立开来
The walls of reality closed. The worlds were sealed.
永远消失了
'gone for ever.
时间领主监控着一切  都不在了
The Time Lords kept their eye on everything. It's gone now.
但时间领主都死了
But they died, the Time Lords!
他们全都死了
All of them, they died.
我是最后的时间领主
I'm the last of the Time Lords.
米娅  拿上密封剂  把破口补好
Mia, take this sealant, fix that rig!
尤里  打开紧急氧气
Yuri, open emergency oxygen.
阿德莱德  别光在那坐着
Adelaide, don't just sit there!
这下好多了  穹顶还是完整的
That's better! The Dome's still got integrity!
3米厚的复合钢板
Ten feet of steel-combination,
利物浦制造  工艺精良
made in Liverpool, magnificent workmanship!
-阻止不了了  不要拿自己陪葬  -不
- It can't be stopped. Don't die with us. - No.
因为有人最近才告诉我  他们说我要死了
Cos someone told me just recently, they said I was gonna die,
他们说  他会敲四下
they said, he will knock four times,
我想我知道是什么意思了
and I think know what that means,
肯定指的不是这里  不是现在
it doesn't mean right here right now!
因为我可没听见有人敲门  你呢
Cos I don't hear anyone knocking, do you?!
你顶多也就敲三下了
Three knocks is all you're getting!
水和电  混在一块可不好
Water and electricity, bad mix!
那么还有什么别的手段
Now then, what else have we got?
可是我们根本斗不过它们
But there's no way to fight them.
热
Heat!
它们用水  我们就用高温
They use water, so we can use heat!
对寒冰勇士管用  对洪魔也管用
Works against the Ice Warriors, Works against the Flood,
强化环境控制  把它们蒸发掉
ramp up the environment controls, steam them!
但你说了  我们会死
But you said we die!
为了未来  为了全人类
For the future, for the human race.
是  但时间是有法则的
Yes, because there are laws, there are Laws of Time.
很久很久以前
Once upon a time
有人掌管着这些法律  但他们死了
there were people in charge of those laws, but they died.
他们都死了
They all died.
你知道还剩下谁吗  我
Do you know who that leaves? Me!
我花了这么多年才想明白
It's taken me all these years to realise,
时间法则归我了
the Laws of Time are mine.
它们要服从我
And they will obey me!
环境控制坏掉了
Environment controls are down!
抱歉了博士  看来历史还有别的想法
Sorry, Doctor, it looks like history's got other ideas.
我还没输
Not beaten yet!
我去外面
I'll go outside!
去看看温度控制器
Look at the heat regulator.
不  我没输  我没输
No, not beaten, not beaten!
你还有太空服  就在旁边的区
You've got spacesuits, in the next section.
我们在对抗的不止洪魔  还有时间本身
We're not just fighting the Flood. We're fighting time itself.
我一定要赢
And I'm gonna win!
冰原那边出事了
Something's happening to the glacier.
快想快想快想  我们还有什么  氧气不足
Think think think think! What have we got? Not enough oxygen!
蛋白质包  没用
Protein-packs? Useless!
冰  冰薄荷  薄荷  荷花
Glacier, glacier mints, minty, Monty,
花好月圆  这个那个这个那个
molto bene, bunny, Bonny, bish-bash-bosh! Baaaaaaah!
这房间  这个房间  看看这个房间
The room, the room, look at the room!
F区  F区有什么
Section F, what's in Section F?
谁知道
Anyone?
-没什么  就是仓库  -放什么的仓库
- Nothing, it's just storage. - Storing what?!
我不知道  风向标  机器人  原子夹
I don't know, weather spikes, robots, atom clamps.
原子夹  原子夹  谁需要原子夹啊
Atom clamps? Atom clamps!? Who needs atom clamps?
我就喜欢好玩的机器人
I love a funny robot!
嘎吱嘎吱
Gadget-Gadget.
-你拿着这个  好孩子  -嘎吱嘎吱
- You take that. Good boy. - Gadget-Gadget.
出发吧
Off we go then!
嘎吱嘎吱
Gadget-Gadget.
快啊  快啊
Come on, come on!
执行船长协议
Implementing Captain's protocol.
阿德莱德  你在干什么
Adelaide? What are you doing?!
我的天啊  五号程序
Oh, my God. Action Five.
如果有必要  我也会对你动手的
If I have to fight you as well, then I will.
核装置已启动并就绪
Nuclear device now active and primed.
快冲啊
Blast off!!
嘎吱嘎吱
Gadget-gadget!
快啊啊啊啊啊
Fastaaaaaaaa!!!!
核装置已进入最后阶段
Nuclear device entering final process.
嘎吱嘎吱
Gadget-gadget!
进去啦
And we're in!
嘎吱嘎吱
Gadget-gadget!
就没人打算谢谢我吗
Isn't anyone going to thank me?
他失去信号了
He's lost his signal.
不知道自己在哪里了
Doesn't know where he is.
那是我的房子
That's my house.
你们还不明白吗
Don't you get it?
现在是2059年11月21日
This is the 21st November 2059.
在地球上也是同一天
It's the same day on Earth.
而且还在下雪  我喜欢雪
And it's snowing. I love snow.
那是什么东西
What is that thing?!
它  里面比...
It's... bigger...
里面比外面大
I mean, it's bigger on the inside!
你到底是谁
Who the hell are you?
去照顾好她
Look after her.
是  长官
Yes, ma'am.
你救了我们
You saved us...
你想想吧
Just think though...
你的女儿  你女儿的女儿
Your daughter, and your daughter's daughter,
你又能见到她们了
you can see them again.
一家团圆
Family reunion!
但我应该死了
But I'm supposed to be dead.
不再是了
Not any more.
可是
But...
苏茜
Susie...
我的外孙女
My granddaughter.
她本该成为的那个人
The person she's supposed to become...
可能永远不会存在了
might never exist now.
不会  阿德莱德船长可以亲自言传身教嘛
Nah! Captain Adelaide can inspire her face to face.
细节不同而已  情节还是一样的
Different details, but the story's the same.
你怎么知道呢
You can't know that.
而如果我的家庭变了
And if my family changes...
整个历史都可能变化
The whole of history could change,
甚至是整个人类的未来
the future of the human race.
谁都不该有那么大的权力
No-one should have that much power.
你还能怎样
Tough.
你应该把我们留在那里
You should have left us there.
阿德莱德  这种事我以前也做过
Adelaide, I've done this sort of thing before.
使使小手段  救几个小人物
In small ways, saved some little people.
但从来没有像你这么重要的  我真厉害
But never someone as important as you. Oh, I'm good!
小人物
Little people?
比如米娅和尤里吗
What, like Mia and Yuri?
谁判定他们就那么不重要  你吗
Who decides they're so unimportant? You?
一直以来
For a long time now,
我都以为我只是个幸存者  但我不是
I thought I was just a survivor, but I'm not.
我是赢家
I'm the winner.
那就是我
That's who I am.
胜利的时间领主
The Time Lord Victorious.
就没人能阻止你了吗
And there's no-one to stop you?
没了
No.
这不对  博士
This is wrong, Doctor.
我不管你是谁  胜利的时间领主错了
I don't care who you are. The Time Lord Victorious is wrong.
这个我说了算
That's for me to decide.
你最好快回家吧
Now, you'd better get home.
门都锁了  毕竟你不在家嘛
Oh, it's all locked up, you've been away.
不过还是小菜一碟
Still, that's easy.
请吧
All yours.
还有你不能做的事吗
Is there nothing you can't do?
以后没有了
Not any more.
我不管你是谁
I don't care who you are.
胜利的时间领主错了
The Time Lord Victorious is wrong.
我做过头了
I've gone too far.
到时候了吗
Is this it?
我的死亡
My death?
到时候了吗
Is it time?
不
No.
每一晚  博士  我们都噩梦不止
Every night, Doctor, we have bad dreams.
但有人告诉我  "他会敲四下"
But I was told, he will knock four times.
因为一个阴影笼罩了所有造物
Because a shadow is falling over creation.
神秘巨祸在黑暗中蠢动
Something vast is stirring in the dark.
我就要死了
I'm going to die.
我的名字  叫做法师
My name is the Master.
随黑暗而来的结局  只有一种
The darkness heralds only one thing...
时间的终结
The end of Time itself.